<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interfaces on Wiki</title>
    <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interfaces on Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lab Streaming Layer(LSL)</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/lsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/lsl/</guid>
      <description>LSL with Mentalab HyperSync Lab Streaming Layer (LSL) is a protocol for the unified collection and synchronization of time-series data from multiple sensors and applications in real time. It provides precise timestamping and seamless network-based sharing of physiological, behavioral, and experimental data. By combining LSL with Mentalab HyperSync, users can acquire, visualize, and record data with sub-millisecond accuracy in just a few simple steps.&#xA;LSL features in Explore Desktop With Explore Desktop users can:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BrainFlow</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/brainflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/interfaces/brainflow/</guid>
      <description>BrainFlow Integration BrainFlow is an open-source library that provides a unified interface for biosignal acquisition across a variety of hardware platforms. It simplifies the process of working with physiological signals such as EEG, EMG, and ECG by offering a consistent API in multiple programming languages including Python, C++, Java, and MATLAB.&#xA;What is BrainFlow? BrainFlow enables:&#xA;Seamless data access across supported biosignal devices Real-time signal processing tools (e.g., filtering, feature extraction) Integration into research workflows and custom applications Cross-platform development using high-level APIs For a deeper overview, visit the official BrainFlow documentation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
