<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integrations on Mentalab Wiki</title>
    <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Integrations on Mentalab Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Supported Software</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/supported-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/supported-software/</guid>
      <description>This list contains EEG analysis software that can import Mentalab Explore data.
In general, many EEG analysis pipelines use EDF file formats. To convert your Mentalab Explore data to EDF, please use the bin2edf command available in our open source API explorepy. If your device has internal memory, it will automatically save data to BIN. If you are using the Bluetooth feature of your Mentalab Explore device, be sure to record to BIN and not CSV on the connected device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LabChart Lightning</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/lightning-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/lightning-installation/</guid>
      <description>If you wish to use Mentalab Explore with LabChart Lightning, please follow the instructions below.
Install LabChart Lightning. Start the program and enter your license key. Then close the program. Download the Mentalab Explore LabChart Lightning plugin. Unzip the plugin and save to Documents/LabChart Lightning/Plugins/Devices. Ensure that your Mentalab Explore device is in pairing mode and blinking blue and that your computer&amp;rsquo;s Bluetooth is on. Then pair your Explore device to the computer through Bluetooth settings (Explore_XXXX).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device Syncing With LSL</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/openvibe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/openvibe/</guid>
      <description>Here is a step-by-step guide on using explorepy and OpenViBE to visualize multiple Mentalab Explore systems simultaneously.
Start two Python consoles and activate a virtual environment for explorepy in both.
Use the push2lsl command to stream data from your Explore device to lab streaming layer (one device per console).
Open an OpenViBE acquisition server and select &amp;ldquo;LabStreamingLayer&amp;rdquo; as the driver. Under &amp;ldquo;Driver Properties&amp;rdquo;, select your Explore device&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;ExG&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Marker&amp;rdquo; streams, selecting only one of the connected Explore devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PsychoPy Builder</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/psychopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/psychopy/</guid>
      <description>Here is a guide to running explorepy inside PsychoPy experiments. We will demonstrate how to record data, set markers, and push to lab streaming layer (LSL).
Install software Download explorepy Download Anaconda. Open the Anaconda prompt and create a virtual environment: conda create -n psychopyenv python=3.6 Activate the virtual environment: conda activate psychopyenv Download explorepy, and extract the files. Edit explorepy Comment out line 215. Open the explorepy-1.6.0\src\explorepy\stream_processor.py script using a text editor (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EEGLab</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/eeglab/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/eeglab/</guid>
      <description>This is a guide to importing Mentalab Explore CSV and BIN files into an EEGLab structure using the Mentalab EEGLab Plugin.
Ensure that you have downloaded the latest version of EEGLab here.To get up and running quickly, here is a quick tutorial video.
Installation To install the Mentalab EEGLab plugin, we recommend using EEGLab&amp;rsquo;s Extension Manager.
Install via Extension Manager Once you have installed EEGLab, following these instructions, open MATLAB and type eeglab into the command line terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
