<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stimulation on Wiki</title>
    <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stimulation on Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PsychoPy</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/psychopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/psychopy/</guid>
      <description>This guide details how to synchronise your Mentalab Explore device with PsychoPy experiments, focusing on high-precision synchronization of event markers using LabStreamingLayer (LSL) in combination with Mentalab Hypersync. This is the recommended approach for robust and accurate data alignment.&#xA;Legacy wired trigger methods are listed at the bottom.&#xA;Prerequisites Before starting, ensure you have the following hardware and software:&#xA;Hardware Mentalab Explore Pro Device: An Explore Pro biosignal acquisition system. Mentalab Hypersync Add-on: This hardware is essential for accurately synchronizing LSL markers from PsychoPy with the Explore device&amp;rsquo;s data stream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSesame</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/opensesame/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/opensesame/</guid>
      <description>This guide details how to synchronize your Mentalab Explore device with OpenSesame experiments, focusing on high-precision synchronization of event markers using LabStreamingLayer (LSL) in combination with Mentalab Hypersync. This is the recommended approach for robust and accurate data alignment.&#xA;Legacy wired trigger methods are listed at the bottom.&#xA;Prerequisites Hardware Mentalab Explore Pro Device: An Explore Pro biosignal acquisition system. Mentalab Hypersync Add-on: This hardware is essential for accurately synchronizing LSL markers from OpenSesame with the Explore device&amp;rsquo;s data stream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>E-Prime®</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/e-prime/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/e-prime/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Hardware Mentalab Explore Pro Device: An Explore Pro biosignal acquisition system. Mentalab Hypersync Add-on: This hardware is essential for accurately synchronizing LSL markers from E-Prime with the Explore device&amp;rsquo;s data stream. Computer: To run E-Prime, LSL, and data recording software for the Explore device. Software E-Prime® 3 E-Prime® 3 LSL package file E-Prime® 3 LSL samples LabRecorder or alternative software that lets you record LSL streams How it Works E-Prime: Runs experiments and can generate event markers during an experiment at onset time, response time or current time LSL package file: The LabStreamingLayer package file provides real-time streaming of data (including markers) with precise timestamps for E-Prime Mentalab Hypersync: The Hypersync suite is used to merge ExG data with event markers via LSL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presentation®</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Hardware Mentalab Explore Pro Device: An Explore Pro biosignal acquisition system. Mentalab Hypersync Add-on: This hardware is essential for accurately synchronizing LSL markers from Presentation® with the Explore device&amp;rsquo;s data stream. Computer: To run Presentation®, LSL, and data recording software for the Explore device. Software Presentation® LabRecorder or alternative software that lets you record LSL streams How it Works Presentation®: Runs experiments and can send event information as a Marker stream via LSL (including information about event type, the event code and uncertainty for the event) Built-in LSL integration: The built-in LabStreamingLayer integration provides real-time streaming of event data with precise timestamps for Presentation® Mentalab Hypersync: The Hypersync suite is used to merge ExG data with event markers via LSL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychtoolbox</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/psychtoolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 10:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/psychtoolbox/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites Hardware Mentalab Explore Pro Device: An Explore Pro biosignal acquisition system. Mentalab Hypersync Add-on: This hardware is essential for accurately synchronizing LSL markers from Presentation® with the Explore device&amp;rsquo;s data stream. Computer: To run Psychtoolbox, LSL, and data recording software for the Explore device. Software Psychtoolbox Matlab LSL for Matlab LabRecorder or alternative software that lets you record LSL streams How it Works Psychtoolbox: Runs experiments from user-written Matlab code and provides access to low-level hardware features to ensure very precise timing (sub-millisecond) and versatile usage Matlab: Psychtoolbox requires Matlab to run LSL for Matlab: The Matlab release for LSL allows users to open and view LSL streams to pull or push data (like Markers) from within Matlab scripts Mentalab Hypersync: The Hypersync suite is used to merge ExG data with event markers via LSL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/5-neuropype-experiment-recorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/integrations/stimulation/5-neuropype-experiment-recorder/</guid>
      <description>&#xD;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
