<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Explore Mobile App on Wiki</title>
    <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explore Mobile App on Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Download and Installation</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/download-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/download-installation/</guid>
      <description>For Android, you can download the app from:&#xA;Google Play Store Direct APK download For iOS/iPadOS, the app can be downloaded from the App Store.&#xA;For any information or assistance, please contact support@mentalab.com and we will assist you further.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usage</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/usage/</guid>
      <description>Please note that currently the app only supports Mentalab Explore Pro 8-channel devices at 250Hz.&#xA;Homepage&#xA;Scan and connect to nearby Explore Devices. Impedance tab&#xA;Inspect impedance values. Assign channel positions. EXG tab&#xA;Visualize ExG data. Dot menu: Adapt visulization settings (y-axis scaling &amp;amp; time window). Record raw ExG data in CSV format. Settings&#xA;See device settings Adjust visualization filters Change sampling rate Disconnect Bottom bar&#xA;Inspect device name, temperature, battery charge </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tests</title>
      <link>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wiki.mentalab.com/explore-mobile-guide/testing/</guid>
      <description>Following are the devices we used to testing:&#xA;Device OS version Lenovo Tab M9 Android 13 Samsung S23 Ultra Android 14 Zenfone 10 Android 14 Pixel 7 Pro Android 15 iPhone 13 iOS 18 Recording Tests The following tests were performed to ensure the recording functionality is working as expected.&#xA;Conducted on Lenovo Tab M9 (Android 13) for 2 hours: 16 channels at 500 Hz sampling rate 16 channels at 250 Hz sampling rate Known bugs No known bugs at the moment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
